[
    {
        "question": "What is String Interpolation in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Concatenating strings using +",
            "Embedding variables and expressions inside a string",
            "Printing strings using console.log",
            "Declaring variables inside strings"
        ],
        "answer": "Embedding variables and expressions inside a string"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which symbol is used for String Interpolation in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "@{ }",
            "#{ }",
            "${ }",
            "{ }"
        ],
        "answer": "${ }"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which quotes must be used for String Interpolation?",
        "options": [
            "Single quotes ' '",
            "Double quotes \" \"",
            "Backticks ` `",
            "Angle brackets < >"
        ],
        "answer": "Backticks ` `"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which symbol is used for single-line comments in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "/* */",
            "<!-- -->",
            "//",
            "#"
        ],
        "answer": "//"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are true about comments in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Comments are used to write the description about application logic",
            "Comments are used to disable the code temporarily",
            "Comments are non-executable code.",
            "All of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
        "question": "Escape sequence characters are used to?",
        "options": [
            "Declare variables",
            "Format string output",
            "Perform calculations",
            "Add comments"
        ],
        "answer": "Format string output"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are tokens in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Errors in code",
            "Smallest individual elements of a program",
            "Only variables",
            "Only keywords"
        ],
        "answer": "Smallest individual elements of a program"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main role of let in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Declares a variable with global scope",
            "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value can be changed",
            "Declares a constant value",
            "Declares a function"
        ],
        "answer": "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value can be changed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the role of const in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value can be changed",
            "Declares a variable usable in all blocks",
            "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value cannot be changed",
            "Declares a global variable only"
        ],
        "answer": "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value cannot be changed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the role of var in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value can be changed",
            "Declares a variable usable in all blocks",
            "Declares a block-scoped variable whose value cannot be changed",
            "Declares a variable usable in all blocks but can not changed."
        ],
        "answer": "Declares a variable usable in all blocks"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an identifier in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "A predefined keyword",
            "A name given to variables, functions, or objects",
            "A numeric value",
            "A JavaScript operator"
        ],
        "answer": "A name given to variables, functions, or objects"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "employeeName",
            "total_Amount",
            "total$salary",
            "total-amount"
        ],
        "answer": "total-amount"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a keyword in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "A user-defined variable name",
            "A predefined word with a fixed meaning in JavaScript",
            "A numeric value",
            "A string literal"
        ],
        "answer": "A predefined word with a fixed meaning in JavaScript"
    },
    {
        "question": "console.log(typeof undefined);",
        "options": [
            "Number",
            "Infinity",
            "Undefined",
            "NaN"
        ],
        "answer": "Undefined"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE about identifiers in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "An identifier can start with a number",
            "An identifier can contain spaces",
            "An identifier can start with a letter, underscore (_), or dollar sign ($)",
            "An identifier can be a JavaScript keyword"
        ],
        "answer": "An identifier can start with a letter, underscore (_), or dollar sign ($)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output when a variable is declared but not assigned any value in JavaScript? let x; console.log(x);",
        "options": [
            "null",
            "0",
            "undefined",
            "Error"
        ],
        "answer": "undefined"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the result when we divide a number by zero in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "undefined",
            "Infinity",
            "ArithmeticException"
        ],
        "answer": "Infinity"
    },
    {
        "question": "The program made up of?",
        "options": [
            "Keywords & Operators",
            "Identifiers & Separators",
            "Constants & Literals",
            "All of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following cases will JavaScript return NaN?",
        "options": [
            "Invalid numeric operations.",
            "Division By zero operation.",
            "Division By zero with negative operation.",
            "if the value is not assiged to variable."
        ],
        "answer": "Invalid numeric operations."
    },
    {
        "question": "console.log(typeof Infinity);",
        "options": [
            "Number",
            "Infinity",
            "Undefined",
            "NaN"
        ],
        "answer": "Number"
    }
]